Guide to the Nell Mondy papers, 1932-2005.
Mondy, Nell papers, 1932-2005
- V. Associations/Institutes (Box 7)
  - Graduate Women in Science (GWIS)
    - College of St. Catherine, St. Paul, MN, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Mount Vernon College, Washington, DC, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Three Arts Club, Chicago, IL, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Chapman University, Orange, CA, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Penn State University, University Park, PA, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - University of San Diego, San Diego, CA, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - St. Thomas College, St. Paul, MN, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Portland, OR, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Alpha Chapter-Rhodes, awarded for excellence; World Who's Who; Speech-50th Year, 1970-1979 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Nominated for VP at National Meeting, Ithaca College, Ithaca, NY, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - VP Speech, Washington, DC; Picture, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - President-Recieved gavel; Letter to members; DAA honor Editorial Board; Office Picture, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - President-Grand Chap., New York, NY 1984 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Board Director; Honor-Fellow IFT; Ivory Coast Speech 1985 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Board Director, Agriculture Committee; Speech on West Africa 1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - 2 Chapter Award in Excellence; Ag Com, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Board of Directors, Agriculture Committee 1988 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Director, Agricultre Committee, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Board of Directors-Senior Director, Agriculture Committee, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Profile: Zu-China, Kim-Korea, Reddy-India, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - International Relations Committe Profile: Frieda Rossouiu-South Africa, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Profile: Maria Lejn-Poland, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Profile: Esther Mensah-Ghana, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Profile: Kulshrestha-India, NM Lectureship; Nell Mondy Organic Laboratory, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Agriculture, International Relations Committee Steir Award: Profile: Viola Graham History, Pat Glorio-Peru, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Agriculture, International Committee: Profile: M. Stone and Schilder, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Cornell Honor: Ulla Uusitalo, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Fellowships Committee, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Coordinator of Awards, 1974-1974 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Committee on Chapter Establishment, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Archivist; Assist. Archivist Jean Smith, 1978-1987 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Ivory Coast Role of Scientific and Engineering Societies in Development, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - International Relations Committee, 1984-1999 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Nomination for Internationl Award Helen H. by Alpha Chapter, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Profiles of International Women Scientists, 1991-1999 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Letters from GWIS National Office for Nell Mondy's Retirement, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Nomination for Vice President, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Vice President, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - President Elect, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - NM President, Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - NM President Clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Professional Skills Roster, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - 50th Year Speech, Kappa Chapter, New Yoek City, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Vice President Speech, GWIS Luncheon, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Vice President; Acceptance Speech as President of National GWIS, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Speech, Ivory Coast, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - 65th Year; Distinguished Members 1986 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Honorary Life Membership, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Alpha Chapter History (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Alpha Chapter Speeches, 1975, 1983, 1985, 1990, 1991, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Award for Excellence, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Nomination for Vice President, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Activities, 1980-1989 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Directory, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Chapter Offices, 1996, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - First National Bank of Ithaca, Trust, 1935-05-31 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - AAAS Meeting in Washington, DC, 1982-01 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Meeting Location, 1978-1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - National Meeting - Ithaca College, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - National Interim Meeting in Boston, 2002-02-16 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - National Meeting in Washington, DC, 2002-06-06-2002-06-09 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Meaning of GWIS (Objectives) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Officer Reports, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Committee Reports, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Report of Fellowship Committee, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - History of the Professional Skills Roster, 1967-1986 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Graduate women in Science (National Meeting Boston), 2004 (Box 14, Folder 80)
  - American Association for Advancement of Science (AAAS)
    - History Milestones Meetings and Presidents, 1940-1996 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Fellows, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - AAAScope (Vice President Gore), 1996 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Campaign Update, New Building, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - General Elections, 1986-1987, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Newsletter, 1983-1984, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - CAIP Correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - CAIP Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - CAIP Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - CAIP Nominating Committee (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - CAIP Consortium Notes I, 1983, 1985, 1986, 1988, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - CAIP Consortium Notes II, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Minutes, Agriculture, Committee Section, 1988-1992 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Agriculture, Food and Renewable Resources, 1994-1997 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Agriculture Committee Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Agriculture Committee (priorities to U.S. government), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Handbook Officers, 1987-1993, 1995-2000 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - International Program, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - AAAS, 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - AAAS, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - AAAS, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - AAAS, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - AAAS, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Annual Meeting in Boston, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Scrapbook of Sigma Delta Epsilon - the Graduate Women's Scientific Fraternity in Biological, Physical, and Mathematical Sciences - covering the years, 1961-1968 (Box 8)
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP)
    - AAUP, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - AAUP, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - AAUP, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - AAUP, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - AAUP, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - AAUP, 1983-1991 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - International Platform Association (IPA)
    - Invitation to join IPA (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Podium, 1988, 1989, 1995, 1997, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - IPA, 1980-1989 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - IPA, 1990-1999 (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - IPA, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Meetings Convention, 1979, 1980, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Food Science Institute
    - Early History of Nutrition and Food Science (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Committee on Courses of Study (Mondy Chair), 1964-05 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - FS Policy Subcommittee Meeting, 1964-05-19 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Washington DC Meeting - Institute of Fod Science, 1964-06 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - FS Policy Subcommittee Meeting, 1964-06-16 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - FS Policy Subcommittee Meeting, 1964-06-30 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - FS Policy Subcommittee Meeting, 1964-07-01 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Proposal for a Single Department of Food Science, 1964-07-07 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Field Meeting Grad Field Food Science, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Membership Grad Field Food Science, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Phi Tau Sigma
    - Mondy Charter Member Phi Tau Sigma, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Mondy Councillor, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Recent Phi Tau Sigma Activities (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Memberships
    - Cryobiology, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - American Dietetic Association, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Kiwanis Club (Box 1, Folder 81)
- VI. Speeches
  - List of Speeches Made, 1958-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Frontiers in Food Research, - "The Relation of Potato Quality to Chemical Composition", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1A)
  - Fourth Triennial conference of the European Association for Potato Research "Flavor of Potatoes as Related to Phenolic Content" - Brest, France, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - PAA Utilization Conference, Michigan, - "Polyphenols and Other Constituents in Relation to Potato Flavor and Color", 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Washington, DC, - "Flavor and Color of Potatoes as Related to Chemical Composition", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 50th GWIS, New York - "Potato Quality Related to Chemical Composition", 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Twin Falls, Idaho, - "The Influence of Boron Application on the Chemical Composition of Potatoes" - Potato Association of America, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Guelph, Ontario Canada, - "The Effect of Potassium Fertilization of Tuber Composition" - Potato Association of America, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cornell - Food Crops, - "Post-Harvest Changes", 1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Grunes Federal Nutrition Labs, - "Human Nutrition and Food", 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Pasco, Washington, - "The Effect of Virus X on Tuber Composition" - Potato Association of America, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Beltsville, MD, - "The Effect of Sprouting and Sprout Inhibition on the Chemical Composition of Potatoes" - Potato Association of America, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fredericton, N.B. Canada, - "The Effect of Nitrogen Fertilization on the Quality of Potatoes" - Potato Association of America, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Orlando, Florida, - "Quality of Potato Tubers as Affected by Cold Temperature" - 62nd Annual Meeting of Potato Association of America, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Japan, - "The Effect of Sprout Inhibition on the Quality of Potatoes" (abstract), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Kyoto, Japan, - "The Effect of Sprout Inhibition on the Quality of Potatoes" - Fifth International Congress on Food Science and Technology, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Birkett-William Lecture, Ouchita University, - "Food, Chemistry, and You", 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - PAA,, Prince Edward Island - "Changes in Nitrogenous Constituents and Minerals of Potato Tubers and Sprout Following Germination in the Light and Dark", 1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Univ. of Wisconsin, - for Extension Agents - "Toxicants in the Food Chain", 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - GWIS/AAAS, DC, - As Vice President Graduate Women in Science - "Food, Chemistry, and You", 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Ithaca College, - "Food, Chemistry, and You, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Peru, - Decennial Anniversary Celebration of the International Potato Center - "Factors Affecting the Nutritional Quality of Potatoes", 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Ireland,, International Food Congress, Dublin - Sixth World Congress at Food Science and Technology - "Effect of Isopropyl N3-Chlorophenyl Carbamate (CIPC) on the Potato Quality", 1983 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Ivory coast, - "Role of Scientific and Engineering Societies in Development", 1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Univ. of IFT, Nigeria, - "Roots and Tubers: Yams, Cassava, Sweet Potato", 1984 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - ACS Rochester - "Food, Chemistry, and You", 1985 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Idaho Potato School, - "Management for Reducing Black Spot Bruise", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cornell Extension - "Factors Affecting Potato Quality", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - China, - "Potato Quality as Related to Sprout Inhibition", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Kiwanis Club, - Ithaca (on Africa), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Nutrition Institute, - "Potatoes: Good and Bad", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Russia, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Singapore,, 7th World Congress of Food Science and Technology- "Effect of Gamma Irradiation on Potato Quality", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - USDA Minn. - "Perspectives of a Woman Scientist in International Agriculture", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - ACS-Los Angeles, - "Effect of Processing on the Phenolic Content of Vegetables", 1988 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - PAA Colorado, - "Effect of Isopropyl N3-Chlorophenyl Carbamate (CIPC) on the Potato Quality", 1988 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Food Science Seminar, - "The Role of the International Food Congress in the World Today", 1988 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Kiwanis Club Ithaca - China, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - GWIS Pursuit of Success, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Women's Club of Ithaca - "Ode to the Potato", 1988 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Indonesia,, Visiting at Gadjah Mada Univ. Bulaksumar - Yogyakarta - "Report of Dr. Nell Mondy", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Food Processors, - "Methods of Preventing Enzymatic Darkening in Potatoes", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Mauritius,, 2nd Triennial African Potato Association, Reduit, Mauritius - "Nutritive Value in Relation to Potato Disorders", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Seminars - Cornell Activities, - "FRIG (Faculty Research Interest Group in DNS)", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - New Zealand, Institute of Food Science and Technology, Christchurch, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - New York State and Penn Potato Growers, - "Factors Affecting Black Spot", 1993 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Willard Straight, - "You Succeed Because You Think Like A Man" 50 years as a Chemist: One woman's experience, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Garden Club, - "The Potato: A Food for the World", 1996 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - International Nutrition Seminar, - "Nigeria: Yams and Soy Milk", 1997 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - International Lectures (titles) (Box 5, Folder 49)
- VII. Workshops
  - AG - Domecon, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Pesticide Residue, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Cornell Summer Institute on Educational Media, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Fritzsche Brothers, Inc., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - ADP, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- VIII. Publications/ Clippings
  - Publications
    - List of Publications (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 133-130 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 129-120 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 119-110 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 109-100 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 99-90 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 89-80 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 79-70 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 69-60 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 59-50 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 49-40 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 39-30 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 29-20 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 29-20 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 19-10 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 9-1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 140 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - 141 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - 142 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - 143 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Research at Cornell, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Publications, 1980-1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Research at Cornell, 1990-1993 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (Box 3)
    Item level description of clippings available in accession file
    - Clippings, 1930-1959
      - Clippings, 1930-1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Clippings, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1960-1969
      - Clippings, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Clippings, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Clippings, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Clippings, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Clippings, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Clippings, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Clippings, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1970-1979
      - Clippings, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Clippings, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Clippings, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Clippings, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Clippings, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Clippings, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Clippings, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Clippings, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Clippings, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1980-1989
      - Clippings, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Clippings, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Clippings, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Clippings, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Clippings, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Clippings, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Clippings, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Clippings, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Paul Harvey (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Clippings, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Clippings, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - 1990-1995
      - Clippings, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Clippings, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Clippings, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Clippings, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Clippings, 1994-2005 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Listings (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Papers Reviewed for Journals (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Chronological File, 1945-1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Chronological File, 1970-1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chronological File, 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Chronological File, 1986-1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Chronological File, 1990-1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- IV. Africa
  - Cornell Africa Committee, 1984-1999
    - Africa Research Group, 1980-1989 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Kenya, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cornell Africa Studies, 1989-1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cornell Africa Committee, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Cornell Africa Committee, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Cornell Africa Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Institute for African Development, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mauritius, 1990
    - Workshop Program, 1990-07-22-27 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence following meeting, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Paper Presented: Nutritional Values in Relation to Potato Disorder, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Photos (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Adventures on Paradise Island: Mauritius Summary, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ivory Coast, 1984
    - Correspondence, 1984-1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Introduction Participants, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Nell Mondy Speech, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Third World Organization for Women in Science, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Nell Mondy's Nomination from Dr. Helen Haller GWIS, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Sharing Science with Africa: Ivory Coast Summary, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - African Regional Seminars, 1980-1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Ivory Coast Reminiscences, Undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Nigeria
    - Newspaper Daily Sketch, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper The Guardian, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper Daily Times, 1983-11 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper New Nigerian, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper New Nigerian, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper, 1984-01 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Soy in Africa, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Kersey Children's Home Newsletter, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Ruth Womack, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Sharon Hawk, 1983- (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Letters from Chief Alma Rohm, 1987-1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Letters to Chief Alma Rohm, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - IITA Cooperates with Kersey Children's Home Soy for Children's Hospital Dr. Wes Root, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Dr. S.R. Singh Gift to Hospital, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - (Soy) Kersey Children's Home (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - University of Ibadan (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - University of IFE (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Research at IITA, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - IITA Correspondence, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Facts about IITA, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Yams and Soy Milk Summary, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Reflections on Africa (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Nigeria Reminiscences, Undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
- X. Cornell
  - Summary First Year, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Will Gortner Letters (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - First Appointment, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Frozen Food Project (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Second Appointment, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Maynard Letter, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Marion Pfund Letter, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Catherine Personius Letter, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Lucile Williamson Letter, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - First Appointment Food and Nutrition, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Second Appointment Food and Nutrition, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Third Appointment Food and Nutrition, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - EM Methods (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Literature Review EM (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Special Literature Review EM (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - EM Picture Potato Cell (+virus X) (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - EM Picture Potato Cell (-virus X) (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - First Scanning EM Picture (FLA) (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - EM (Bud-Cortex) (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - 100 years Agricultural Research (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Bulletin-Fruit and Vegetable (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Bulletin-Meat and Poultry Canning (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Teaching-Instructor for Chem Institute (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Teaching Aides-Coffee/Vanilla (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Teaching Aids-Seafood (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Teaching Aides-Color Chart (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Meat Bulletin (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Karen Sowizral "Acid Whey Hydrolysis" (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Elizabeth Sprague Eastern College Science Conference A (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Elizabeth Sprague Eastern College Science Conference B (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Elizabeth Sprague Honors Thesis C (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Elizabeth Sprague Class Report D (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Chris Hone-PPO Fruit and Vegetable (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Robin Hoebel- Inc. Green and Yellow Vegetables-Lower Cancer Deaths (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Cathy Adams-Color in Potato Chips (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Mary Dillon- Ethylene Dibromide (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Cathy Mauro-Leaf Protein Concentrate (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Wendy Reymond-Inhibition Root Growth by Aluminum (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Elizabeth Rosen-Natural Antioxidants (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Ken Singhel-Aspartame (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Lisa Klein-Effect of Cooking Methods on Nutritive Value Potatoes (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Jonine Lark-Sweeteners and their Toxicity (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Mondy and Dillett-Natural Toxicants (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Potato Varieties (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Potato Varieties (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Potato Varieties (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Annual Report, 1954-1960 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Annual Report, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Annual Report, 1962-1962 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Annual Report, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Annual Report, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Annual Report, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Annual Report, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Annual Report, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Annual Report, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Annual Report, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Annual Report, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Annual Report, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Annual Report, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Annual Report, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Annual Report, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Annual Report, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Annual Report, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Annual Report, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Annual Report, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Annual Report, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Annual Report, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Annual Report, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Annual Report, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Annual Report, 1995-07-1996-04-15 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 30)